[
    {
       "question": "... are specific to Jupyter Notebooks and provide a convenient way to interact with and control the behavior of the notebook environment",
       "options": ["Magics", "Stories", "Lullabies"],
       "correct_answer": "Magics"
     },
     {
      "question": "How do I differentiate line and cell magics?",
      "options": ["% and %%", "& and &&"],
      "correct_answer": "% and %%"
    },
    {
      "question": "You can view a list of available magics and their documentation by running ... in a Jupyter Notebook cell.",
      "options": ["%lsmagic", "lsmagic", "%%lsmagic"],
      "correct_answer": "%lsmagic"
    },
    {
      "question": "If I write my code in Jupyter Notebook, can I quickly save it as python script?",
      "options": ["yes, by using magics", "no, manual copy/paste is needed", "yes, by changing notebook's extension to .py"],
      "correct_answer": "yes, by using magics"
    },
    {
      "question": "... less common term for decimal",
      "options": ["binary", "denary", "float"],
      "correct_answer": "denary"
    },
    {
      "question": "Take an already well performing model from a problem space similar to yours and then customize it to fit better into your problem, this is ...",
      "options": ["reinforcement learning", "transfer learning"],
      "correct_answer": "transfer learning"
    },
    {
      "question": "Transfer learning allows us to take the patterns, also called ..., another model has learned from another problem and use them for our own problem.",
      "options": ["weights", "layers"],
      "correct_answer": "weights"
    },
    {
      "question": "A ... is a deep learning model that adopts the mechanism of self-attention",
      "options": ["bidirectional encoder", "transformer", "markov chain"],
      "correct_answer": "transformer"
    },
    {
      "question": "Transformers are designed to process ... input data",
      "options": ["non-sequential", "sequential"],
      "correct_answer": "sequential"
    },
    {
      "question": "... processes all the entire input at once",
      "options": ["RNN", "Transformer"],
      "correct_answer": "Transformer"
    },
    {
      "question": "GELU stands for Gaussian Error Linear Unit. It is an ... ... that is commonly used in neural networks, esp in NLP",
      "options": ["bias", "activation function"],
      "correct_answer": "activation function"
    },
    {
      "question": "Acronym 'ACID' in RDBMS refers to a set of 4 key properties: ...?",
      "options": ["Atomicity, Consistency, Isolation, and Durability", "Advanced, Concurrency, Isolation, Database", "Allgemeine, Communism, Isolation, Datenbank"],
      "correct_answer": "Atomicity, Consistency, Isolation, and Durability"
    },
    {
      "question": "ACID is an acronym that refers to the set of 4 key properties that define a ... : Atomicity, Consistency, Isolation, and Durability",
      "options": ["transaction", "contract", "negotiation"],
      "correct_answer": "transaction"
    },
    {
      "question": "RDBMS: CAP theorem in simple words...",
      "options": ["you are not allowed to have everything at once and have to choose any 2 options out of three at any time", "you are allowed to have everything at once, a system must be stable each moment in the time - stability", "CAP theorem is not related to RDBMS"],
      "correct_answer": "you are not allowed to have everything at once and have to choose any 2 options out of three at any time"
    },
    {
      "question": "Each transaction has a level of ...",
      "options": ["isolation", "rollback", "commit"],
      "correct_answer": "isolation"
    },
    {
      "question": "... transaction provides a full isolation",
      "options": ["repeatable read", "serializable", "read committed", "read uncommitted"],
      "correct_answer": "serializable"
    },
    {
      "question": "In SQL, the ... and ... statements are used to define the boundaries of a transaction",
      "options": ["BEGIN / COMMIT", "BEGIN TRANSACTION / COMMIT", "BEGIN / END"],
      "correct_answer": "BEGIN TRANSACTION / COMMIT"
    },
    {
      "question": "in RDBMS, how many typical / most common <strong>normalization forms</strong> exist?",
      "options": ["1NF, 2NF, 3NF", "1NF, 2NF, 3NF, 4NF, 5NF", "it depends on DB architecture, there are not such terms like xNF in RDBMS"],
      "correct_answer": "1NF, 2NF, 3NF"
    },
    {
      "question": "In RDBMS, when each field of the table contains just one value + no composite data, it is ...",
      "options": ["1NF", "2NF", "3NF"],
      "correct_answer": "1NF"
    },
    {
      "question": "in RDBMS, there is a table 'Employees', it has a field 'Employee' and contains value 'Ivanov Ivan Ivanovich', this value has 1NF view",
      "options": ["No, 1NF has no composite data as values", "yes"],
      "correct_answer": "No, 1NF has no composite data as values"
    },
    {
      "question": "1NF + primary key + lack of duplicates is ...",
      "options": ["2NF", "3NF"],
      "correct_answer": "2NF"
    },
    {
      "question": "2NF + all the attributes in the table depend only on primary key",
      "options": ["3NF", "developer's sweet dream", "4NF"],
      "correct_answer": "3NF"
    },
    {
      "question": "in RDBMS, when data in a table is related directly to table's primary key and not to records located in other tables is indication of ...",
      "options": ["2NF", "3NF", "1NF"],
      "correct_answer": "3NF"
    },
    {
      "question": "in RDBMS, 3NF allows duplications of records",
      "options": ["No, because each next NF is build over the previous one, the 2NF prohibits duplication of records", "Yes, it allows, NF are isolated from each other", "There is no such constraint on records duplication"],
      "correct_answer": "No, because each next NF is build over the previous one, the 2NF prohibits duplication of records"
    },
    {
      "question": "in Python, Boolean values (True and False) are a subtype of integers",
      "options": ["yes", "no"],
      "correct_answer": "yes"
    },
    {
      "question": "In the context of RDBMS, ... is a file that contains a set of SQL statements that, when executed, recreate the database structure and/or data",
      "options": ["Dump", "Content"],
      "correct_answer": "Dump"
    },
    {
      "question": "in RDBMS, it is often used for backup or migration purposes",
      "options": ["dump", "rollback"],
      "correct_answer": "dump"
    },
    {
      "question": "in RDBMS, index speeds up search in DB and slows down saving into DB",
      "options": ["yes", "no"],
      "correct_answer": "yes"
    },
    {
      "question": "in RDBMS, index is stored in a form of a table",
      "options": ["yes", "no"],
      "correct_answer": "yes"
    },
    {
      "question": "... is a Python library for generating fake data, and it is used in Python scripts or applications to create realistic but non-sensitive data for testing or development purposes",
      "options": ["pgfutter", "Faker"],
      "correct_answer": "Faker"
    },
    {
      "question": "in Transformers, self-attention, ... function preserves the order of the input values from ow to high",
      "options": ["softmax", "linear"],
      "correct_answer": "softmax"
    },
    {
      "question": "In Python 'self' is ...",
      "options": ["attribute", "method"],
      "correct_answer": "attribute"
    },
    {
      "question": " ... Datatypes, ... Devices, .... Shapes are three big errors in PyTorch's Deep Learning scientists usually make",
      "options": ["Wrong", "Complex"],
      "correct_answer": "Wrong"
    },
    {
      "question": "In Jupyter Notebooks, ... ... are special commands that provide additional functionality beyond what standard Python syntax offers",
      "options": ["magic commands / magics", "extra commands / extras", "command line commands / clc"],
      "correct_answer": "magic commands / magics"
    },
    {
      "question": "In Jupyter Notebooks, there are ... types of magics: ..., ...., ....",
      "options": ["two: line magics and cell magics", "three: line magics, cell magics and full magic"],
      "correct_answer": "two: line magics and cell magics"
    }
     
         
   ]
   